<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>HASALD</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>The Hong Kong Association for Self-Access Learning and Development</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:37:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Presentation: Timothy Mossman from Simon Fraser University</title>
		<link>/presentation-timothy-mossman-from-simon-fraser-university/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=76</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Thursday, 25 May 2017Speakers: Timothy Mossman from Simon Fraser University This was an overview of the services the SLC at SFU provides to shape student success: workshops, consultations, print and online resources, as well as through classroom collaborations with faculty.&#160; Tim described their unique multi-tiered approach to providing these services, which involves professional staff, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Thursday, 25 May 2017</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Timothy Mossman from Simon Fraser University</strong></p>



<p>This was an overview of the services the SLC at SFU provides to shape student success: workshops, consultations, print and online resources, as well as through classroom collaborations with faculty.&nbsp; Tim described their unique multi-tiered approach to providing these services, which involves professional staff, graduate students, and student volunteers. The focus was on English as an Additional Language (EAL) support and services that he coordinates, including workshops, non-credit courses, and the conversation partners program.&nbsp; He concluded by sharing the results of an evaluative pilot study designed to examine how the current designation “EAL” is understood by the many English language learners who seek help from the Student Learning Commons and the possible implications of this study for how their services are marketed and delivered services to their diverse international and domestic EAL clientele. A lively discussion was held afterwards in which Tim asked the following questions:</p>



<ol>
<li>How do you communicate/market to students what resources exist at the university to assist them to learn English in an academic environment?</li>



<li>How do you identity what gaps exist in your support (if any) for students and how do you fill those gaps?</li>



<li>What supports and services have students initiated (if any) that you have built for them?</li>
</ol>



<p>How do you foster interdisciplinary collaborations with Faculties and Units?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: Roxanne Miller (formerly Wong)</title>
		<link>/presentation-roxanne-miller-formerly-wong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 05:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Tuesday, 25 Apr 2017Speakers: Roxanne Miller (formerly Wong) ‘Roxifyonline’ is an automated feedback system designed to give students help with essay writing.&#160; This program is the product of Roxanne’s PhD research and was designed for use by EFL/ESL learners. It has been in use by her students for the two years. The programme went [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Tuesday, 25 Apr 2017</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Roxanne Miller (formerly Wong)</strong></p>



<p>‘Roxifyonline’ is an automated feedback system designed to give students help with essay writing.&nbsp; This program is the product of Roxanne’s PhD research and was designed for use by EFL/ESL learners. It has been in use by her students for the two years. The programme went through 4 different rounds of beta testing and will soon be available online.&nbsp;The presenters provided student comments on the program, a short demo and a link to use it with teachers’ classes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: Adam Forrester from HK PolyU</title>
		<link>/presentation-adam-forrester-from-hk-polyu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=80</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Tuesday, 21 Feb 2017Speakers: Adam Forrester from HK PolyU Adam Forrester is the Project Leader of the MOOC developed by the ELC,&#160;English@Work in Asia. This MOOC was first launched in October 2015, and is now on its third run on the edX platform.&#160;Adam’s talk taught us how MOOCs have developed, their characteristics, and presented [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Tuesday, 21 Feb 2017</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Adam Forrester from HK PolyU</strong></p>



<p>Adam Forrester is the Project Leader of the MOOC developed by the ELC,&nbsp;<strong>English@Work in Asia</strong>. This MOOC was first launched in October 2015, and is now on its third run on the edX platform.&nbsp;Adam’s talk taught us how MOOCs have developed, their characteristics, and presented two types of MOOC – the cMOOC and xMOOC. &nbsp;Adam also discussed where MOOCs might be heading in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: Shari Lughmani from HK PolyU</title>
		<link>/presentation-shari-lughmani-from-hk-polyu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=82</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Wednesday, 11 Jan 2017Speakers: Shari Lughmani from HK PolyU Shari spoke about the recent rise of English across the Curriculum in Hong Kong universities and increased resources allocated towards General Education (GE) provision and literacy. She said that due to the impetus for inter-institutional collaboration and relevant pedagogical development, the Hong Kong’s University Grants [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Wednesday, 11 Jan 2017</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Shari Lughmani from HK PolyU</strong></p>



<p>Shari spoke about the recent rise of English across the Curriculum in Hong Kong universities and increased resources allocated towards General Education (GE) provision and literacy. She said that due to the impetus for inter-institutional collaboration and relevant pedagogical development, the Hong Kong’s University Grants Committee launched the Competitive Funding Scheme on Teaching and Learning 2012-2015 which has resulted in new English across the curriculum initiatives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>News: Seasons Greetings e-Card</title>
		<link>/news-seasons-greetings-e-card/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 05:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=84</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:  Monday, 12 Dec 2016Topic: James wrote and sent a Seasons Greetings e-Card to all HASALD members with information of the next event printed on it]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:  Monday, 12 Dec 2016<br>Topic: James wrote and sent a Seasons Greetings e-Card to all HASALD members with information of the next event printed on it</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: HKU, PolyU and CityU OPTIMUS Team</title>
		<link>/presentation-hku-polyu-and-cityu-optimus-team/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=86</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Friday, 25 Nov 2016Speakers: HKU, PolyU and CityU OPTIMUS Team – David Gardner, Ken Lau, Kevin Pat, Jovi Chan, James King, Jane Robbins, Hebe Wong For this HASALD gathering, all of the OPTIMUS Team were in attendance to present and discuss this new online project. The team shared the main goal of the&#160;Online Project [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Friday, 25 Nov 2016</strong><br><strong>Speakers: HKU, PolyU and CityU OPTIMUS Team – David Gardner, Ken Lau, Kevin Pat, Jovi Chan, James King, Jane Robbins, Hebe Wong</strong></p>



<p>For this HASALD gathering, all of the OPTIMUS Team were in attendance to present and discuss this new online project. The team shared the main goal of the&nbsp;<em>Online Project for the Improvement of University Speaking</em>&nbsp;Project (OPTIMUS) of providing Hong Kong tertiary students with an online, self-access resource for the improvement of their English speaking skills and related that OPTIMUS is the product of a large UGC-funded project conducted collaboratively by HKU, CityU and PolyU. OPTIMUS is centred on a database of more than 60 video exemplars of authentic best-practice speaking from expert and peer presenters. The user interface allows learners a large degree of independence to tailor usage to their preferred learning styles and needs. From this presentation participants learned about the key pedagogical features of the project and also discussed some of the logistical hurdles. The user interface was also demonstrated and its potential applications in self-access learning were also discussed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>News: HASALD AGM and Presentation</title>
		<link>/news-hasald-agm-and-presentation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:  Oct 2016Speakers: Dr Chan Wing Shing (Electronic Engineering, CityU) and Dr Hebe Wong (CityU ELC)Topic: HASALD AGM and Presentation In this presentation HASALD members learned that for ten years the English Language Centre and the Electronic Engineering Department of City University of Hong Kong have worked closely together to provide language support beyond the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:  Oct 2016</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Dr Chan Wing Shing (Electronic Engineering, CityU) and Dr Hebe Wong (CityU ELC)</strong><br><strong>Topic: HASALD AGM and Presentation</strong></p>



<p>In this presentation HASALD members learned that for ten years the English Language Centre and the Electronic Engineering Department of City University of Hong Kong have worked closely together to provide language support beyond the classroom for Engineering students. Dr Chan explained from the perspective of a discipline teacher the importance of developing communication skills for Engineering students and the challenges faculty members face when doing so. Hebe Wong focussed on the recent projects she has worked on with the Engineering department to illustrate different modes of collaboration with academic departments and to provide language support beyond the classroom for students at both undergraduate and postgraduate levels. The two speakers concluded by summarising their experience in inter-departmental collaboration in language enhancement projects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: Visit from Ritsumeikan University</title>
		<link>/presentation-visit-from-ritsumeikan-university/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 05:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=74</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Thursday, 29th Oct 2015Time:&#160; 18:30 to 19:30Speakers: Michael SHAWBACK, Chie HOSOKAWA, and Saeko DANMATSU from Ritsumeikan UniversityTopic:&#160;Visit from Ritsumeikan University Click&#160;here&#160;for more information.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Thursday, 29th Oct 2015</strong><br><strong>Time:&nbsp; 18:30 to 19:30</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Michael SHAWBACK, Chie HOSOKAWA, and Saeko DANMATSU from Ritsumeikan University</strong><br><strong>Topic:&nbsp;Visit from Ritsumeikan University</strong></p>



<p>Click&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/hasald.pdf">here</a></strong>&nbsp;for more information.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20151029_182840.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20151029_182840.jpg?w=300&amp;h=169" alt="20151029_182840" class="wp-image-264" /></a></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20151029_190952.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20151029_190952.jpg?w=300&amp;h=169" alt="20151029_190952" class="wp-image-265" /></a></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20151029_193409.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20151029_193409.jpg?w=300&amp;h=169" alt="20151029_193409" class="wp-image-266" /></a></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: Evaluating the Usefulness of Writing Materials in Self-access Language Learning from the Learners’ Perspective</title>
		<link>/presentation-evaluating-the-usefulness-of-writing-materials-in-self-access-language-learning-from-the-learners-perspective/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 05:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=72</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Thursday, 7th May 2015Speakers: SHEN JiayuTopic:&#160;Evaluating the Usefulness of Writing Materials in Self-access Language Learning from the Learners’ Perspective Abstract: Self-access language learning (SALL) promotes learner autonomy and cultivates life-long learners. Due to the commercially-bought self-access materials housed at the City U Self Access Centre (SAC), their usefulness to SALL is not assured. Hence, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Thursday, 7th May 2015</strong><br><strong>Speakers: SHEN Jiayu</strong><br><strong>Topic:&nbsp;Evaluating the Usefulness of Writing Materials in Self-access Language Learning from the Learners’ Perspective</strong></p>



<p><strong>Abstract:</strong></p>



<p>Self-access language learning (SALL) promotes learner autonomy and cultivates life-long learners. Due to the commercially-bought self-access materials housed at the City U Self Access Centre (SAC), their usefulness to SALL is not assured. Hence, there is a need to evaluate materials, especially writing materials due to the increasingly importance of writing in university study. This study explored students’ perceptions of and attitudes towards the SALL writing materials and the City U SAC. The results of a qualitative and quantitative study of 32 student users will be presented, as well as the implications of the findings regarding the SALL materials.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker’s bio:</strong></p>



<p>SHEN Jiayu is a postgraduate student at the City University of Hong Kong. Her major is English Studies. She recently finished her Master’s thesis and was supervised by Dr. Lindsay Miller. Her work is similar to a pilot study done on the SALL materials housed in City U’s SAC. She chose this topic because of her vast experience with self-access learning and use of SAC materials while studying for her Bachelor’s degree.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20150507_191911.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><img decoding="async" src="https://hasald.files.wordpress.com/2010/12/20150507_191911.jpg?w=300&amp;h=169" alt="20150507_191911" class="wp-image-259" /></a></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presentation: Study abroad and its implications for self access practices: An overview of relevant research</title>
		<link>/presentation-study-abroad-and-its-implications-for-self-access-practices-an-overview-of-relevant-research/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[HASALD]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 05:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://hasald4.wordpress.com/?p=70</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Date:&#160; Tuesday, 17th March 2015Speakers: Thomas HaywardTopic:&#160;Study abroad and its implications for self access practices: An overview of relevant research Abstract: This presentation provides an overview of study abroad (SA) research, looking at how the studies are conceived and their overall aims. This research has traditionally been informed by issues in the wider field of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Date:&nbsp; Tuesday, 17th March 2015</strong><br><strong>Speakers: Thomas Hayward</strong><br><strong>Topic:&nbsp;Study abroad and its implications for self access practices: An overview of relevant research</strong></p>



<p><strong>Abstract:</strong></p>



<p>This presentation provides an overview of study abroad (SA) research, looking at how the studies are conceived and their overall aims. This research has traditionally been informed by issues in the wider field of second language acquisition, and the central focus has been on proficiency outcomes and why there is such variance between learners. There have been a number of theories devised to account for this outcome, some focusing on learner-internal variables and others looking at contextual factors that can play a role in the amount of language a sojourner ultimately acquires while abroad. These various research approaches will be discussed, and then relevant lessons will be drawn for how self access can help prepare sojourners for their study abroad experience.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker’s bio:</strong></p>



<p>Thomas Hayward is a final-year PhD candidate in the English Department of City U. His thesis is an ethnographic case study of the internationalization practices of a Taiwanese university, and he is using a discourse analysis framework to determine where agency exists in the implementation of internationalization policy at the micro-contextual level. More broadly, he has an interest in second language identities and learner autonomy, particularly in study abroad contexts. An American citizen by birth, Mr. Hayward has lived and worked in several countries in Europe and East Asia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
